

linkedin.com/in/ben-liu github.com/ben196888 (+61) 413 188 912 ben196888@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Ben Liu is focusing on web apps developing these 5 years. He worked in JavaScript with ReactJS for 3.5 years and NodeJS for 2 years. He is always passionate about new technology and likes to learn new ideas from developer events and open source projects. He is not only an avid problem solver but also a good autodidact who is keen on more than one solution.

## **SKILLS**

Skills JavaScript, TypeScript, Docker, Golang, Python

Libraries ReactJS, Redux, RxJS, NodeJS, Angular, EmberJS, Restify, Serverless

Databases Mongo, Redis, Firebase, PostgreSQL

Tools Jenkins, Buildkite, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Elasticsearch

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Predictive Hire, Melbourne, Australia

Oct. 2018-

Software Engineer

- Designed and built a chatbot website to inspire 1 investor and 10 potential customers.
- Led 2 Devs to integrate applicant tracking system to extend 33% of enterprise customers.
- Reduced 600% CI/CD run time by decoupling micro-services in same integration test rate.
- Created a process and guided 1 Scientist to deliver NLP models for enterprise customers.
- Led 1 Scientist and 1 Intern to transit proof-of-concept scripts to the product code base.

## Tabcorp, Melbourne, Australia

Jan. 2017-Sep. 2018

Developer

- Led 3 Devs and 1 DevOps to build an API service for 5000 transactions per min in 4 weeks.
- Solved 3rd party API issues across the Ops team and Devs team on production in one day.
- Reduced DOM unit tests 3500% execution time by replacing headless chrome with JSDOM.
- Increased unit tests coverage rate from 75% to higher than 95% by adding 100+ test cases.
- Resolved the browser crashed issue by throttling when receiving 150+/s data stream.
- Unblocked bottleneck to render 500% more transactions per second by queueing the stream.

### HopebayTech, Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2014-Oct. 2016

Software Engineer

- Developed 100+ users internal web services, integrated G Suite and Slack.
- Created CI pipelines for 5 projects, integrated Jenkins, Gitlab, and Slack.
- Dockerized 5 web services, 3 databases, and 2 cross-compiling build system in 3 projects.
- Centralized system monitoring platform for 200-unit servers, integrated Elasticsearch.

# **EDUCATION**

 ${\bf Bachelor's\ degree,\ Mathematics}$ 

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

2009 - 2014